Office of the Dean, Fletcher School Records UA054
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Dean Subject Files, 1933 -- 1994; UA054.002; 2.4 Linear Feet
  - University Steering Com. [Edmund A. Gullion], 1964 -- 1978; UA054.002.009.00015 (Box UA054 Shared 1)
    Steering Committee Reports and info
  - Commencement [Theodore Eliot], 1979 -- 1985; UA054.002.009.00016 (Box UA054 Shared 1)
    Commencement Correspondence of Dean Theodore Eliot
  - Deanship, 1978 -- 1979; UA054.002.009.00017 (Box UA054 Shared 1)
    Deanship Search Committee Documents
  - Fletcher Memos, 1983 -- 1985; UA054.002.009.00018 (Box UA054 Shared 1)
    Memos from Dean ad Interim Roche and Dean Eliot
  - For the Record, 1983 -- 1985; UA054.002.009.00019 (Box UA054 Shared 1)
    Dean Theodore Eliot, "For the Record" memos/letters
  - Ginn Library, 1981 -- 1989; UA054.002.009.00020 (Box UA054 Shared 1)
    Letters regarding Ginn Library
  - Memos: TLE - J Mayer, 1979 -- 1985; UA054.002.009.00021 (Box UA054 Shared 1)
    Correspondence between Dean Eliot and Tufts President Mayer
  - Secretaries of State Project [ Theodore Eliot], 1979 -- 1985; UA054.002.009.00022 (Box UA054 Shared 1)
    Secretary of State Conference
  - Van der Beugel Fellowship [Jeswald Salacuse], 1986 -- 1994; UA054.002.009.00023 (Box UA054 Shared 1)
    Van der Beugel Fellowhip correspondence by Dean Salacuse
  - Asia Foundation (Small Nations Project), 1989; UA054.002.009.00024 (Box UA054 Shared 1)
    Asia Foundation correspondence (Dean Salacuse)
  - Bentley/Ciber, 1986 -- 1994; UA054.002.009.00025 (Box UA054 Shared 1)
    Dean Salacuse correspondence with Bentley College, CIBER reporting
  - Fletcher/International Business Center of N.E.; Technology Proposal to US Dept. of Education, 1986 -- 1994; UA054.002.009.00026 (Box UA054 Shared 1)
    Dean Salacuse
  - Fletcher Roundtable, 1991; UA054.002.009.00027 (Box UA054 Shared 1)
    Fletcher Roundtable: Defining a New World Order
  - Fletcher School Mission, 1933 -- 1980; UA054.002.009.00028 (Box UA054 Shared 1)
    Documents regarding the Fletcher School's mission
  - Ford Foundation, 1986 -- 1994; UA054.002.009.00029 (Box UA054 Shared 1)
    Ford Foundation Grants and Correspondence (under Dean Salacuse)
  - Ginn Library [1 of 2], 1982 -- 1986; UA054.002.010.00001 (Box UA054 Shared 2)
    Documents regarding Fletcher's Ginn Library
  - Ginn Library [2 of 2], 1934 -- 1988; UA054.002.010.00002 (Box UA054 Shared 2)
  - Humphrey Program, 1987 -- 1990; UA054.002.010.00003 (Box UA054 Shared 2)
    Humphrey Fellowship Program
  - Mayer - Research Funding, 1976 -- 1992; UA054.002.010.00004 (Box UA054 Shared 2)
    Correspondence from Tufts Presiden Jean Mayer
  - Niger Project, 1984 -- 1990; UA054.002.010.00005 (Box UA054 Shared 2)
    Niger Integrated Livestock Production Project: Final Report
  - Olin Center for Media Quality, 1989 -- 1990; UA054.002.010.00006 (Box UA054 Shared 2)
    John M. Olin Foundation
  - Oral History Project (Prof. Ra'anan) J. Howard Pew Freedom Trust Grant, 1987 -- 1989; UA054.002.010.00007 (Box UA054 Shared 2)
    Oral History Project--Interntional Security Studies Program
  - Product Liability Final Report, 1987 -- 1988; UA054.002.010.00008 (Box UA054 Shared 2)
    Round Table on the Impact of US Product Liability Law on US Export Trade and International Competitiveness Final Report
  - Presidents' Conference (Talloires, September 12-16, 1988), UA054.002.010.00009 (Box UA054 Shared 2)
    Conference documents
  - Sri Lanka USAID, 1989; UA054.002.010.00010 (Box UA054 Shared 2)
    Correspondence regarding sri Lanka Policy Support Unit Project
  - Sub-Saharan Africa AID, 1988; UA054.002.010.00011 (Box UA054 Shared 2)
    AID Grant for "Linkages Between Policy Reform and Natural Resources Management in Sub-Saharan Africa"
  - Title 6 - Foreign Language, 1989 -- 1990; UA054.002.010.00012 (Box UA054 Shared 2)
    Correspondence regarding Title VI Foreign Language Fellowship Program
  - US Institute of Peace Proposals, 1987 -- 1988; UA054.002.010.00013 (Box UA054 Shared 2)
    USIP Grant Correspondence
  - US Institute of Peace/Peace-Keeping Working File, 1988 -- 1991; UA054.002.010.00014 (Box UA054 Shared 2)
    USIP related documents
  - US Institute of Peace (Jeswald Salacuse), 1990 -- 1991; UA054.002.010.00015 (Box UA054 Shared 2)
    USIP Grant acceptance
- Executive Faculty Meetings, 1966 -- 2000; UA054.003; 6.0 Linear Feet
  This series includes memorandum, memorandum drafts, agendas, minutes, correspondence, and recommendations for PhD candidacy among other things.
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  - Executive Faculty Meeting, 1966 -- 1968; UA054.003.010.00016 (Box UA054 Shared 2)
    Meeting Notes
  - Executive Faculty Meeting, 1969; UA054.003.010.00017 (Box UA054 Shared 2)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting, 1970; UA054.003.010.00018 (Box UA054 Shared 2)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting [1 of 2], 1971; UA054.003.010.00019 (Box UA054 Shared 2)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting [2 of 2], 1971; UA054.003.010.00020 (Box UA054 Shared 2)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting, 1972; UA054.003.010.00021 (Box UA054 Shared 2)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting [1 of 2], 1973; UA054.003.010.00022 (Box UA054 Shared 2)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting [2 of 2], 1973; UA054.003.010.00023 (Box UA054 Shared 2)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting, 1974; UA054.003.010.00024 (Box UA054 Shared 2)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting, 1975; UA054.003.011.00001 (Box 11)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting, 1976 -- 1977; UA054.003.011.00002 (Box 11)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting, 1978; UA054.003.011.00003 (Box 11)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting [1 of 2], 1979; UA054.003.011.00004 (Box 11)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting [2 of 2], 1979; UA054.003.011.00005 (Box 11)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting, 1980; UA054.003.011.00006 (Box 11)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting, 1981; UA054.003.011.00007 (Box 11)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting [1 of 3], 1982; UA054.003.011.00008 (Box 11)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting [2 of 3], 1982; UA054.003.011.00009 (Box 11)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting [3 of 3], 1982; UA054.003.011.00010 (Box 11)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting [1 of 2], 1983; UA054.003.011.00011 (Box 11)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting [2 of 2], 1983; UA054.003.011.00012 (Box 11)
  - Executive Faculty meeting [1 of 2], 1984; UA054.003.011.00013 (Box 11)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting [2 of 2], 1984; UA054.003.011.00014 (Box 11)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting, 1985; UA054.003.011.00015 (Box 11)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting, 1986; UA054.003.011.00016 (Box 11)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting [1 of 2], 1987; UA054.003.011.00017 (Box 11)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting [2 of 2], 1987; UA054.003.011.00018 (Box 11)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting [1 of 2], 1988; UA054.003.012.00001 (Box 12)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting [2 of 2], 1988; UA054.003.012.00002 (Box 12)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting [1 of 2], 1989; UA054.003.012.00003 (Box 12)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting [2 of 2], 1989; UA054.003.012.00004 (Box 12)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting [1 of 3], 1990; UA054.003.012.00005 (Box 12)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting [2 of 3], 1990; UA054.003.012.00006 (Box 12)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting [3 of 3], 1990; UA054.003.012.00007 (Box 12)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting [1 of 2], 1991; UA054.003.012.00008 (Box 12)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting [2 of 2], 1991; UA054.003.012.00009 (Box 12)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting [1 of 3], 1992; UA054.003.012.00010 (Box 12)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting [2 of 3], 1992; UA054.003.012.00011 (Box 12)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting [3 of 3], 1992; UA054.003.012.00012 (Box 12)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting [1 of 2], 1993; UA054.003.012.00013 (Box 12)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting [2 of 2], 1993; UA054.003.012.00014 (Box 12)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting [1 of 2], 1994; UA054.003.012.00015 (Box 12)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting [2 of 2], 1994; UA054.003.012.00016 (Box 12)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting [1 of 2], 1995; UA054.003.012.00017 (Box 12)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting [2 of 2], 1995; UA054.003.012.00018 (Box 12)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting, 1995; UA054.003.013.00001 (Box UA054 Shared 3)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting [1 of 3], 1996; UA054.003.013.00002 (Box UA054 Shared 3)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting [2 of 3], 1996; UA054.003.013.00003 (Box UA054 Shared 3)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting [3 of 3], 1996; UA054.003.013.00004 (Box UA054 Shared 3)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting, 1997; UA054.003.013.00005 (Box UA054 Shared 3)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting, 1998; UA054.003.013.00006 (Box UA054 Shared 3)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting, 1999; UA054.003.013.00007 (Box UA054 Shared 3)
  - Executive Faculty Meeting, 2000; UA054.003.013.00008 (Box UA054 Shared 3)
- Full Faculty Meetings, 1963 -- 2000; UA054.004; 1 Volumes
  The series includes memorandum, agendas, minutes, correspondence, recommendations regarding granting degrees, and information about prize nominees among other things.
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1963 -- 1966; UA054.004.013.00009 (Box UA054 Shared 3)
  - Full Faculty Meetings, 1967 -- 1968; UA054.004.013.00010 (Box UA054 Shared 3)
  - Full Faculty Meetings, 1969 -- 1971; UA054.004.013.00011 (Box UA054 Shared 3)
  - Full Faculty Meetings, 1972; UA054.004.013.00012 (Box UA054 Shared 3)
  - Full Faculty Meetings, 1973; UA054.004.013.00013 (Box UA054 Shared 3)
  - Full Faculty Meetings, 1974; UA054.004.013.00014 (Box UA054 Shared 3)
  - Full Faculty Meetings, 1975; UA054.004.013.00015 (Box UA054 Shared 3)
  - Full Faculty Meetings, 1976; UA054.004.013.00016 (Box UA054 Shared 3)
  - Full Faculty Meetings [1 of 2], 1977; UA054.004.013.00017 (Box UA054 Shared 3)
  - Full Faculty Meetings [2 of 2], 1977; UA054.004.013.00018 (Box UA054 Shared 3)
  - Full Faculty Meetings, 1978; UA054.004.013.00019 (Box UA054 Shared 3)
  - Full Faculty Meetings, 1979; UA054.004.014.00001 (Box UA054 Shared 4)
  - Full Faculty Meetings, 1980; UA054.004.014.00002 (Box UA054 Shared 4)
  - Full Faculty Meetings, 1981; UA054.004.014.00003 (Box UA054 Shared 4)
  - Full Faculty Meetings, 1982; UA054.004.014.00004 (Box UA054 Shared 4)
  - Full Faculty Meetings, 1983; UA054.004.014.00005 (Box UA054 Shared 4)
  - Full Faculty Meetings, 1984; UA054.004.014.00006 (Box UA054 Shared 4)
  - Full Faculty Meetings, 1985; UA054.004.014.00007 (Box UA054 Shared 4)
  - Full Faculty Meetings, 1986; UA054.004.014.00008 (Box UA054 Shared 4)
  - Full Faculty Meetings, 1987; UA054.004.014.00009 (Box UA054 Shared 4)
  - Full Faculty Meetings, 1988; UA054.004.014.00010 (Box UA054 Shared 4)
  - Full Faculty Meetings, 1989 -- 1990; UA054.004.014.00011 (Box UA054 Shared 4)
  - Full Faculty Meetings, 1991 -- 1992; UA054.004.014.00012 (Box UA054 Shared 4)
  - Full Faculty Meetings, 1993 -- 1994; UA054.004.014.00013 (Box UA054 Shared 4)
  - Full Faculty Meetings, 1995 -- 1996; UA054.004.014.00014 (Box UA054 Shared 4)
  - Full Faculty Meetings, 1997 -- 1998; UA054.004.014.00015 (Box UA054 Shared 4)
  - Full Faculty Meetings, 1999 -- 2000; UA054.004.014.00016 (Box UA054 Shared 4)
- Annual Reports, 1944 -- 1999; UA054.005; 0.5 Linear Feet
  The series consists of annual reports and information used to compile them.
  20 years from date of creation. Open for research.
  - Annual Reports, 1944 -- 1958; UA054.005.014.00017 (Box UA054 Shared 4)
    Annual Reports
  - Annual Report to the President, 1969; UA054.005.014.00018 (Box UA054 Shared 4)
  - Annual Reports, 1971 -- 1974; UA054.005.014.00019 (Box UA054 Shared 4)
  - Annual Reports, 1974 -- 1979; UA054.005.014.00020 (Box UA054 Shared 4)
  - Annual Reports, 1981 -- 1987; UA054.005.014.00021 (Box UA054 Shared 4)
  - Annual Reports, 1987 -- 1991; UA054.005.014.00022 (Box UA054 Shared 4)
  - Annual report to president, 1991 -- 1992; UA054.005.015.00001 (Box 15)
    Open for research.
  - 1992, UA054.005.015.00002 (Box 15)
  - Annual report to Sol Gittleman, 1992 -- 1993; UA054.005.015.00003 (Box 15)
  - Annual report to Sol Gittleman, 1993 -- 1994; UA054.005.015.00004 (Box 15)
  - Annual reports, 1993 -- 1994; UA054.005.015.00005 (Box 15)
  - Annuals, 1994 -- 1995; UA054.005.015.00006 (Box 15)
  - Annuals, 1995 -- 1996; UA054.005.015.00007 (Box 15)
  - FSLD Annual report, 1996 -- 1997; UA054.005.015.00008 (Box 15)
  - [Annual Report], 1997 -- 1998; UA054.005.015.00009 (Box 15)
  - Annual report, 1999; UA054.005.015.00010 (Box 15)
- Speeches, 1986 -- 2005; UA054.006; 0.5 Linear Feet
  Speeches given by the Dean of the Fletcher School at convocations, commencements, class days, installation ceremonies, memorials, and other events, 1986-2005. "State of the Fletcher School" addresses are also included.
  While some document titles include the speaker's name, others simply read "Dean." Given the date range of these materials, all speeches are likely associated with the following deans: Jeswald W. Salacuse, Dean, 1986-1994; Richard B. Mancke, Dean ad interim, 1994-1995; John R. Galvin, Dean, 1995-2000; Joel P. Trachtman, Dean ad interim, 2000-2001; Stephen W. Bosworth Dean, 2001-2013.
  - Speeches, 1986 -- 1989; UA054.006.016.00001; Salacuse, Jeswald (Box 16)
  - Speeches, 1990 -- 1991; UA054.006.016.00002; Salacuse, Jeswald (Box 16)
  - Speeches, 1992; UA054.006.016.00003; Salacuse, Jeswald (Box 16)
  - Speeches, 1993; UA054.006.016.00004; Salacuse, Jeswald (Box 16)
  - Speeches, 1994; UA054.006.016.00005; Mancke, Richard (Box 16)
  - Speeches, 1995 -- 2001; UA054.006.016.00006; Galvin, John; Bosworth, Stephen (Box 16)
  - Speeches, 2002 -- 2005; UA054.006.016.00007; Bosworth, Stephen (Box 16)
- Additional accessions, UA054.000296
  - Photo Albums, 2006; UA054-001 (Box data_value_missing_5e27d04c468291736fbb684196971fc9, Box 1)
  - Plaque given to Bosworth and Beyond Boundaries book, 2011; UA054-002 (Box data_value_missing_4e38412b28a94830cca63ef455f650ae, Box 2)
    Sent to the DCA from Linda Warner in the Office of the Dean - gifts given to Dean Stephen Bosworth.
- 2016 accessions, UA054.008; 1 Digital Object(s)
  This series is arranged in order of accession.
  This series is open for research.
  This series contains a recording of the event, "A Celebration of the Life of Ambassador Stephen Warren Bosworth," held at Memorial Church at Harvard University on February 20, 2016.
  - A Celebration of the Life of Ambassador Stephen Warren Bosworth, February 20, 2016; UA054.008.00001; 1 Digital Object(s); 278.2 Megabytes
    Recording of an event at Memorial Church, Harvard University honoring former Dean of the Fletcher School Stephen Warren Bosworth. Featured speakers include Lawrence Bacow, Albert del Rosario, Han Sung Joo, Richard Haass, Morton Abramowitz, Olivia Spenard, Allison Bosworth, Aso Tavitian, Peter Ackerman, Graham Allison, Brian Bosworth, William Rutledge, and Hilary Pennington.
    Immediate Source of Acquisition
    Transferred by the Office of the Dean of the Fletcher School, 2016, accession 2016.122.
- James Stavridis files, 2013 -- 2018; UA054.009; Stavridis, James G.; 63.6 Gigabytes; 20 Digital Object(s) 20 digital objects comprising 28 files.
  This series is arranged in received order, with folder titles provided by the donor.
  This series contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list.
  Transferred by the Office of the Dean of the Fletcher School, 2018, accession UA-2019-024.
  This series contains the files of former Dean of the Fletcher School James Stavridis, including a spreadsheet of radio, TV, web, and print media coverage of Stavridis; lists of blogs and op-eds written by Stavridis; speeches given by Stavridis at Commencement, Class Day, and Convocation; annual reports to the Provost by fiscal year from 2013 through 2018; a zip folder of faculty meetings documentation; a Fletcher School organization chart from 2016; a biography of Admiral Stavridis; and a self-evaluation by Stavridis.
  - Media, circa 2013 -- 2018; UA054.009.00001; 5 Digital Object(s); 0.86 Megabytes
    This file contains a spreadsheet of radio, TV, web, and print media coverage of James Stavridis, as well as lists of blogs and op-eds written by Stavridis.
    Records on digital media have been stabilized and made available via Box. Note that files were not converted for access and all may not be viewable in Box. Please contact DCA for further details.
  - Commencement and Class Day, 2014 -- 2018; UA054.009.00002; 8 Digital Object(s); 0.94 Megabytes
    This file contains speeches given by James Stavridis at Commencement and Class Day.
  - Convocation, 2013 -- 2017; UA054.009.00003; 6 Digital Object(s); 1.3 Megabytes
    This file contains speeches given by James Stavridis at Convocation.
  - Annual Reports, Faculty Meetings, Misc, 2013 -- 2018; UA054.009.00004; Stavridis, James G.; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object containing 9 files.; 77.5 Megabytes
    Closed 20 years from date of creation.
    This file contains annual reports to the Provost by fiscal year from 2013 through 2018, a zip folder of faculty meetings documentation, a Fletcher organization chart from 2016, a biography of Admiral Stavridis, and a self-evaluation by Stavridis.